<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pedagogical Terms on Speech School</title>
    <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pedagogical Terms on Speech School</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dark vs Bright</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/dark-vs-bright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/dark-vs-bright/</guid>
      <description>Phonation    A major speech pathology common for men is overly dark phonation. The darkness or brightness of the timbre refers to how the energy is distributed around the harmonics, the brighter the timbre the more energy is distributed to higher harmonics.
The brightness of phonation is a result of vocal cord tension. Higher vocal cord tension carries more energy to higher harmonics resulting in a brighter timbre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falsetto</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/falsetto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/falsetto/</guid>
      <description>In falsetto the vocal cord ligaments remain unmoved and only the mucosa layer bounces. To produce a clean falsetto the entire vocal cord has to come into contact. But this is difficult and untrained falsetto singers leave a gap in the middle where air continuously escapes.
       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head Voice</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/head-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/head-voice/</guid>
      <description>Chest voice is where the vocal cords make the same motion as they do in normal speaking. Likewise with falsetto, the vocal cords make a different motion in head voice leading to a different sound being produced. What this motion is wikipedia doesn&amp;rsquo;t say. However, it results in a sound where more energy is distributed to the higher harmonics compared to head voice.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathy Voice</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/breathy-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/breathy-voice/</guid>
      <description>In breathy voice the vocal cords are held further apart with lower tension than normal. Breathy voice is when the vocal cords do not make full closure as they their mobile ends are not brought fully together. This allows more air to escape and can be heard as a softer sound, with more random noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belting</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/belting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/belting/</guid>
      <description>Belting is where one carries the chest voice above the natural transition to the head voice. However, this necessitates singing with intensity. For an example, look to Brendon Urie who belts most of his songs.
Hack    Thinking of the pejorative &amp;ldquo;Woo Girls&amp;rdquo;, you can get an idea of the upper limit of your pitch for your chest voice by shouting WOO! The pitch should peek in the middle of the woo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timbre</title>
      <link>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/timbre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://speechschool.tech/pedagogy/timbre/</guid>
      <description>Timbre describes the quality of the sound source which is best visualized by the shape of the spectral slice. Good timbre will have a spectral slice where the harmonics are balance in size, smooth, and are shaped nicely.
  Slice of the i (Fleece) vowel below       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
